Finding aid to the Special Days A-Z records CA.MS.00110
Smith College Archives
Special Days A-Z records
1880-2002
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00110
1.042 linear feet (3 containers)
The records of the Special Days vary in their coverage of events. For some special days the only recognition of its existence is the presence of the folders. However, other folders contain records of the special day's beginnings on campus. The Valentine's Day and Thanksgiving Day folders contain information about past celebrations with newspaper clippings and reports, photographs, and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown
Biographical / Historical
As an institution Smith College has many traditions, some with history since its inception. One of the earliest special days celebrated at Smith College was Ivy Day. Still celebrated, Ivy Day is a day in which departing seniors plant ivy cuts on the Smith grounds, symbolizing their seed of knowledge, in hopes that it will flourish. Today, cuts are taken from vines around campus and given to first-year students in anticipation of their own Ivy Day celebration.
Many of those traditions include Special Day celebrations for students, staff, faculty, and parents. Included in the Special Days boxes are the Father's Day folders containing programs, POPS! concert programs, photographs, letters, and newspaper clippings. The change from Father's Weekend to Parent's Weekend and then Family Weekend is documented with the information contained in these folders.
Halloween, Thanksgiving, Easter, Float Night are special days included within the folders. And the repertoire of special days continues to grow as Smith College adds new special day traditions to its old ones: Celebration of Sisterhood and Otelia Cromwell Day. Each celebration seeks to acknowledge and diversify, celebrating what is present and what is to come. Smith College, having a history of celebrating, embracing, renewing and creating traditions, will carry several of them into the future and create several more.
Scope and Contents
The degree to which folders contain information varies. For some special days the only recognition of its existence is the presence of the folders, perhaps containing as little as a single photograph or a single event program. In such case, the Sophian may be a good place to look for further information.
However, other folders contain records of the special day's beginnings on campus. The Valentine's Day and Thanksgiving Day folders contain information about past celebrations with newspaper clippings and reports, photographs, and memorabilia. In general, information for present day special day celebrations is not as complete as those of earlier celebratory years. For instance, though the Celebration of Sisterhood still takes place, the documents contain information for only 2 years. Similarly, Float Night is a continued Tradition that is documented for only 2 individual years. Additional files on Float Night are available in 80. Athletics Records.
The folders are arranged alphabetically. Two special days, Christmas and Mountain Day have their own boxes. These have separate finding aids.
Women college students--Massachusetts--Northampton--Social life and customs.; Smith College--History--Sources.; Smith College--Students--Social life and customs.
- Africa Day, 1994 (Box 3079)
- All College Picnic, 1986-1994 (Box 3079)
- April Fool's Day, 1981 (Box 3079)
- Armistice Day, 1935-1940 (Box 3079)
- Celebration of Sisterhood, 1993-1995 (Box 3079)
- Commencement, general, 1896-1987 (Box 3079)
- Convocation, Barbara Bush recieves Honorary Degree, 1989 (Box 3079)
- Easter, 1889-1952 (Box 3079)
- Environmental Events, 1968-1970 (Box 3079)
- Family Weekend, 1992-2000 (Box 3079)
- Fathers Weekend, implementation, 1949 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1951 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1952 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1953 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1954 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1955 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1956 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1957 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1958 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1959 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1960 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1961 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1962 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1963 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1964 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1965 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1966 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1967 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1968 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1969 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1970 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1971 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1972 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend, 1973 (Box 3079)
- Father's Weekend Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 3079)
- Float Night, 1952-1998 (Box 3079)
- Freshman Day, 1967-1982 (Box 3079)
- Halloween, 1890-1951 (Box 3080)
- Halloween Photographs, 1888-1994 (Box 3080)
- Harvest Weekend, 1979-1989 (Box 3080)
- Homecoming, 1990-1992 (Box 3080)
- Hoop Rolling, 1914 (Box 3080)
- Illumination, 1995-1996 (Box 3080)
- Ivy Day, 1884-1984 (Box 3080)
- May Day, 1884-1951 (Box 3080)
- Memorial Day, 1882-1940 (Box 3080)
- No Diet Day, 1994 (Box 3080)
- Octoberfest, 1994-1995 (Box 3080)
- Opening Convocation (September), All College Meeting (January), 1949 (Box 3080)
- Otelia Cromwell Day, 1989-2002 (Box 3080)
- Parent's Weekend, 1974-1991 (Box 3080)
- Pre College Day, 1967-1970 (Box 3080)
- Sophomore Carnival, undated (Box 3080.1)
- Spirit Week, 1982 (Box 3080.1)
- Spring Weekend, 1988 (Box 3080.1)
- Thanksgiving, 1880-1942 (Box 3080.1)
- Turkey Trot, 1987 (Box 3080.1)
- Valentine's Day, 1895-1951 (Box 3080.1)
- Week of Prayer, 1916 (Box 3080.1)
- Winter Weekend, 1987-1992 (Box 3080.1)
- Women's Week, 1982-1985 (Box 3080.1)
- Women's Weekend, 1972-1980 (Box 3080.1)